Privacy Notice | Robert Half                                       

Privacy Notice
==============

Welcome to the Robert Half websites and the Robert Half mobile application together with any materials and services available therein, and successor site(s) thereto (individually referred to as the “Site” or collectively as the “Sites”), which are operated by Robert Half Inc. and its subsidiaries (“Robert Half” or “we” or “us”). This Privacy Notice (“Notice”) describes how Robert Half may use and disclose information that we may collect about all users and viewers through the Sites. The Terms of Use (“Terms”) state the terms and conditions governing your use of and access to the Sites and constitute a legally binding contract between you and Robert Half. The Terms incorporate any additional terms and conditions posted by Robert Half through the Sites, or otherwise made available to you by Robert Half. PLEASE REVIEW THESE TERMS AND NOTICE CAREFULLY. YOUR ACCESS TO AND/OR USE OF THE SITES CONSTITUTES YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF, AND CONSENT TO BE BOUND BY, THESE TERMS AND NOTICE. IF YOU DO NOT ACCEPT AND CONSENT TO BE BOUND BY THESE TERMS AND NOTICE, THEN YOU MUST NOT USE OR ACCESS THE SITES. We may change these Terms and/or Notice from time to time by notifying you of such changes by any reasonable means, including by posting revised Terms and/or Notice through the Sites. Any such changes will not apply to any dispute between you and us arising prior to the date on which we posted the revised Terms or Notice incorporating such changes, or otherwise notified you of such changes. In the event of a conflict between these Terms and/or Notice, and any other applicable terms or agreement fully executed by you and Robert Half (“Other Terms”), the Other Terms shall control. The “Last Updated” legend above indicate when the Notice was last changed. We may, at any time and without liability, modify or discontinue all or part of the Sites (including access to the Sites via any third-party links); or offer opportunities to some or all Site users. Any changes will become effective when we post the revised Notice on the Sites. Your use of the Sites following these changes means that you accept the revised Notice. 

When you use or register with the Sites, we may collect certain information that identifies you as an individual or relates to an identifiable individual (“Personal Information”). Categories of Personal Information: The categories of Personal Information we may collect include: With respect to visitors of the Site, we collect the following categories of information from your browser or directly from you when you visit our Site: Internet activity, such as your browsing activity on the Site, your IP address, cookies, installed plug-ins, and javascript object (“Data Collection Technologies”). This information, including geolocation data, is collected automatically. Regarding your IP address, this is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer by your Internet Service Provider. An IP address may be identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever a user accesses the Sites, along with the time of the visit and the pages visited. We use IP addresses for purposes such as calculating usage levels, diagnosing server problems, and administering the Sites. We may also derive your approximate location from your IP address. Geolocation data Identifiers if you wish to download certain reports like our salary guides, in which case you will need to provide your first and last name, and email Professional information if you wish to download certain reports like our salary guides, in which case you will need to provide your job title With respect to job applicants, our employees, and independent contractors who use the Sites (“Candidates”), we collect the following categories of information from you: Identifiers, such as your name and contact information (email, address (mailing and home) and phone number), and any login ID or email address and password created by you Professional or career-related information and education information, such as your job search criteria and preferences, your availability to work, your work experience, educational history, your skills, reference information, background check information, pay / compensation expectations, ability to work in the United States, languages spoken, and other information contained in your resume Emergency contact information consisting of full name and phone number Information protected against security breaches such as bank information if you work with us and elect to be paid via direct deposit consisting of bank account numbers and direct deposit information Characteristics of Protected Classifications Under California or Federal Law including gender, age, and military/veteran status With respect to individuals who are business clients or prospective clients of Robert Half who use the Sites (“Customers” or “Prospective Customers”) and any corporation, partnership or other entity on behalf of which a Customer or Prospective Customer is using the Sites, collectively also referred to as “you” and “your”), we collect the following categories of Personal Information from you or from our service providers such as job boards: Identifiers such as your name, business phone number, and work email Professional or employment-related information such as your company name, department, and job title Information protected against security breaches such as bank and payment information if we render services to you, depending on how you elect to pay for services rendered With respect to vendors, we collect the following categories of Personal Information from you or Robert Half’s business contacts who may wish to recommend you: Identifiers such as your name, business phone number, and work email Professional or employment-related information such as your company name, department, and job title Information protected against security breaches such as bank account information, so we can pay you for providing products or services to Robert Half With respect to marketing recipients and Prospective Customers, we collect the following categories of Personal Information from you, from our service providers such as job boards, or from information that is publicly available on the internet: Identifiers such as your name, business phone number, and work email Professional or employment-related information such as your company name, department, and job title Sources of Personal Information. We collect the following categories of Personal Information from the following sources: Directly From California consumers: (a) identifiers; (b) professional or career / employment related information; (c) information protected against security breaches; (d) emergency contact information; (e) characteristics of protected classifications under California or Federal law. Data Collection Technologies (described above): (a) Internet information; (b) Geolocation data. Other sources including Robert Half partners, co-sponsors of events attended or organized by Robert Half, third parties from whom we have purchased business contact information, and from publicly accessible websites, such as company’s website, professional network services, or press releases. By providing your mobile phone number to us, you opt in and consent to receive text messages from us, which includes but is not limited to text messages sent through an automatic telephone dialing system. Consent to receive marketing text messages is not required as a condition of working with us. If you do not wish to receive marketing text messages, do not provide us with your mobile phone number or opt out pursuant to Section 11, below. 

We specify below the business and commercial purposes for which we use Personal Information. We use Personal Information to register you with the Sites, to provide you with information regarding job opportunities and career-related information, to manage our relationship with you, to develop and carry out marketing activities, to gather your feedback and suggestions, and to otherwise provide you with requested information or services. We may from time to time use your Personal Information to send you automated email messages, text messages (message and data rates may apply), or marketing materials regarding our services, including employment information. We may also use Personal Information for our business purposes, such as data analysis, audits, protecting the Sites from abuse, and improving our services. In addition to the above purposes, we use your information as described in the section below titled "DISCLOSURES OF PERSONAL INFORMATION". 

We have not sold any of your Personal Information in the preceding twelve (12) months. We have engaged in the “sharing” of personal information (as defined in the California Privacy Rights Act) about consumers in the preceding 12 months. With regard to Candidates, we share the following categories of Personal Information with our advertising partners: Identifiers consisting of your email address Professional or employment-related information consisting of your company name You have the right to opt-out of the sharing of your personal information. To opt out, you can do the following: use your browser controls to opt out go directly to our partners listed below to disable social media tracking and analytics on this device use the [Digital Advertising Alliance’s consumer choice tool](https://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2&lang=EN) to opt out of certain interest-based advertising Please note that these opt out tools are limited to the device and web browser used to opt out because they work off of your device ID or browser ID. If you utilize another device or browser, you will need to opt out on each device and browser. If you block or clear cookies from your browser, that may remove the opt out setting, requiring you to opt out again. Opt Out From Partners We and our partners collect information about your online activity when you interact with our sites and applications. To opt out, you can use your browser controls or go directly to our partners listed below to disable tracking and analytics on this device. Facebook To opt out of Facebook ad tracking and analytics, [follow the Facebook opt out instructions here](https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217). Google  To opt out of Google ad tracking and analytics, you can choose to [block certain ads](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/2662922#stop_goog_p13n), or opt out or adjust ad personalization in [Google’s ad settings](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated). Instagram  To opt out of Instagram ad tracking analytics, please follow the instructions below: •  Launch the Instagram app on your mobile device. •  Go to Settings: Tap on your profile icon in the bottom right corner to go to your profile. Then, tap on the menu icon (three horizontal lines) in the top right corner. •  Navigate to Settings: Scroll down and select "Settings" from the menu options. •  Access Ads Settings: In the Settings menu, tap on "Ads". •  Manage Ad Preferences: Here, you'll find options related to ad personalization and data settings. You can manage your ad interests and the information Instagram uses to show you ads. •  Opt Out of Tracking: Look for an option similar to "Ad Activity" or "Data About Your Activity from Partners" and toggle it off. This setting prevents Instagram from using data collected from third-party websites and apps you've used to personalize your ads. LinkedIn  For LinkedIn members, to opt out of LinkedIn ad tracking and analytics, [please make your selections here](https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/advertising-data). Your changes may take 24 hours to become effective and even after your opt-out is effective, you may continue to see ads that feature an option to manage your advertising preferences, including to opt out of interest-based advertising. Non-members can opt out of LinkedIn's and its service providers' tracking of visits to LinkedIn for targeted advertising purposes [by visiting this page here](https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls). Click on the “Opt-out of Targeted Advertising” link and follow the instructions. Microsoft  To opt out of Microsoft ad tracking analytics, [follow the Microsoft opt out instructions here](https://account.microsoft.com/privacy/ad-settings/signedout). X (formerly Twitter) ) To opt out of X ) ad tracking and analytics, [follow the X opt out instructions here](https://twitter.com/settings/account/personalization). YouTube  To opt out of YouTube ad tracking analytics, follow the YouTube opt out instructions [here](https://www.youtube.com/account_privacy). 

For business and commercial purposes, Robert Half may disclose to third parties the following categories of Personal Information: Identifiers such as your name and email address Characteristics of protected classifications under California or Federal law such as gender Internet or other electronic activity information such as network activity information or information obtained from your device like browsing history on the Sites, IP address, search history on the Sites, your interaction with an advertisement, installed plug-ins, and javascript objects on your device. Information protected against security breaches like your direct deposit or bank account information so that workers can be paid and Customers can pay us. Geolocation data Professional, career, or employment-related information Education information Robert Half may disclose such Personal Information to the following categories of third parties: Service Providers. We may share Personal Information with our third-party service providers who perform business functions and services on our behalf, such as the provider of Robert Half’s customer relationship management solution. Customers and Prospective Customers. Customers and Prospective Customers may request professional and employment-related information for purposes of evaluating a Candidate’s credentials, skills and experience. Customers may also need to approve and process timesheet information for Candidates. Candidates. We may share Personal Information of our Customers or Prospective Customers to Candidates such as when a Candidate must know information about whom to contact when going on an interview or to a job with a Customer or Prospective Customer. As required or appropriate by law. We may disclose Personal Information to regulatory authorities, government authorities or courts to comply with applicable laws, the service of legal process, or if we reasonably believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law requiring such disclosure; (b) protect the rights or property of Robert Half or its affiliated companies; (c) prevent a crime or protect national security; or (d) protect the personal safety of the users or the public. Business transfers. We also may disclose or transfer information to a third party in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings). Subsidiaries. Protiviti Inc. is a business solutions, internal audit and consulting firm that is also a wholly owned subsidiary of Robert Half. Robert Half may share Customer data with Protiviti for the business purpose of allowing Protiviti to propose a managed business service offering that would bring together consulting expertise (Protiviti) and highly skilled specialized staffing resources (Robert Half) to address a Customer’s business needs. 

“Other Information” is any information that does not reveal your specific identity or does not directly relate to an identifiable individual. We may collect Other Information in a variety of ways, including: Through your browser or device: Certain information is collected by most browsers or automatically through your device, such as your Media Access Control (MAC) address, computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system name and version, device manufacturer and model, language, date, and Internet browser type and version. We use this information to ensure that the Sites function properly. Using pixel tags and other similar technologies: Pixel tags (also known as web beacons and clear GIFs) may be used to, among other things, track the actions of Site users and email recipients, market our services to you, measure the success of our marketing campaigns and compile statistics about Site usage and response rates. Analytics: We use third-party analytics providers such as Google Analytics on the Sites. Google Analytics uses cookies and similar technologies and IP address to collect and analyze information about use of the Services and report on activities and trends. Google Analytics may also collect information regarding the use of other websites, apps and online resources. You can learn about Google’s practices by going to [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners), and opt out by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on, available at [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). We have also engaged Inspectlet to analyze the activities of visitors to this Site, and Inspectlet’s authorized use of cookies and other tracking technologies enable it to have access to Personal Information of visitors to this Site. Such access to and use of Personal Information by Inspectlet is governed by Inspectlet’s privacy policy, available at [https://www.inspectlet.com/legal#privacy](https://www.inspectlet.com/legal#privacy). Site Security: We use the reCAPTCHA service provided by Google to protect the Site and your submissions via internet submission forms on this Site. reCAPTCHA uses the following to evaluate your use of the Site: IP address, your device type and information about your device, cookies placed on your device (such as from Google), language and date information, installed plug-ins, and javascript objects. Your use of reCAPTCHA on the Site is subject to the Google [Terms](https://policies.google.com/terms) and [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy). Please note that we may use and disclose Other Information for our business purposes. 

What Are Cookies? Cookies are pieces of information stored on the computer or mobile device that you are using. Cookies allow us to collect information such as browser type, time spent on the Site, pages visited, registrations, submissions, demographics, information requests, language preferences, and other traffic data. We use the information for security purposes, to recognize your device, to facilitate navigation, to display information more effectively, and to personalize your experience. We also gather statistical information about use of the Site to enhance its functionality, understand how it is used and assist us with resolving questions about it. We may also use cookies and other technologies in online advertising campaigns to track responses to our ads. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, most browsers allow you to automatically decline cookies, or be given the choice of declining or accepting a particular cookie (or cookies) from a particular site. If, however, you do not accept cookies, you may experience some inconvenience in your use of the Site. Cookies cannot spread viruses or harm your computer. With respect to how long a cookie stays on your computer or mobile device, some cookies are session cookies that expire once you close your browser while others are persistent cookies which stay on your device until you delete them, or they expire. 

Cookies Settings

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads regarding our services when you access and use other websites, based on information relating to your use of the Sites. To do so, these companies may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser (including through use of pixel tags). By utilizing the Sites, you consent to the use of cookie or other tracking technologies to serve you retargeted advertising. Data collected may be shared with third-party vendors for cross device linking and advertising purposes. If you would like to learn more about cross device linking or opt out, please refer to the “[Opt Out From Partners](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/privacy.html#3)” area of Section 3 above. If you would like more information about opting out of this advertising in desktop and mobile browsers on the particular device on which you are accessing this Notice or this type of advertising, please visit [http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt\_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) and [http://www.aboutads.info/](http://www.aboutads.info/). 

This Notice does not address, and we are not responsible for, the privacy, information or other practices of any third parties, including any third party operating any site or service to which the Sites link, or any device through which you access the Sites. 

We use reasonable organizational, technical and administrative measures designed to protect Personal Information within our organization. Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure, please immediately notify us in accordance with the "[CONTACT US](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/privacy.html#contact)" section below. 

If you no longer want to receive marketing-related emails from us on a going-forward basis, you may opt-out by using the mechanism contained in each such email. Otherwise, you may unsubscribe by doing any of the following: Fill out the online [Unsubscribe form](https://cloud.email.roberthalf.com/prefs?qs=b982db443ec99b147806f54f338aa3b1cc0b18eb39d23b6c) Call [1 (888) 744-9202](tel:18887449202) 

If you no longer wish to receive marketing-related texts from us on a going-forward basis, you may opt-out by texting “STOP” to us at any time. You may text “HELP” to us or call [1 (888) 744-9202](tel:18887449202) for assistance relating to text messages we send. For more information, you may also text HELP to short code 37938. 

We keep your Personal Information for as long as needed or permitted in light of the purpose(s) for which it was obtained. The criteria used to determine our retention periods include (i) for as long as we have an ongoing relationship with you; (ii) as required by a legal obligation to which we are subject to; or (iii) as advisable in light of our legal position (such as in regard of applicable statutes of limitations, litigation, or regulatory investigations). We may delete Personal Information for inactive accounts from our database, subject to any applicable legal or regulatory obligations. Furthermore, we may delete Personal Information from our database at any time and without providing any reason. 

We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under 16 years old and we do not "sell" or "share," as those terms are defined under CCPA/CPRA (defined below), the Personal Information of children under 16 years old. If we become aware that we have received or collected Personal Information about a child under 16 years old, we will delete that Personal Information as soon as possible. 

We do not sell Personal Information as defined under Nevada law. Nevada residents may email questions regarding our practices relating to Personal Information to [\[email protected\]](https://www.roberthalf.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). 

The Sites are controlled and operated by us from the United States and is not intended to subject us to the laws or jurisdiction of any state, country or territory other than that of the United States. 

Based on your state of residence, you may have the right under the laws of that jurisdiction to request that Robert Half take certain actions with regard to your personal information. If you would like to exercise any such rights, you may do so in any of the following ways: Submit your request online by clicking the following link and filling out the form provided: [Robert Half North America Data Privacy Rights Webform](https://privacyportal-eu.onetrust.com/webform/84d54614-589b-4dad-9735-b7274fe31d97/d2354eaa-41c8-45c6-a1c4-00f2c753041e); or Call our Customer Support team toll-free at [+1 (800) 803-9336](tel:18008039336). Certain states also provide their residents the right to appeal the declination of a privacy request. If you are a resident of one of these states and your request is declined, you may appeal that decision by submitting a new request through one of the above methods and selecting “Appeal” as the Request Type when prompted. Please note that this option is currently only available to the residents of select states. 

If you are a California resident, you have the right, subject to certain exceptions detailed in the California Consumer Privacy Act, as amended by the California Privacy Rights Act (“CCPA/CPRA”) and other applicable laws and regulations, to: request access to your Personal Information, including information about specific pieces of Personal Information we have collected about you. If you wish to know the categories of Personal Information we have collected, the categories of sources from which we have collected your Personal Information, the business or commercial purpose for collecting or sharing your Personal Information, and the categories of third parties to whom we disclose Personal Information, please see the foregoing sections of this Privacy Notice, including but not limited to Sections 1, 2, and 4. request deletion of your Personal Information; however, to the extent permitted by applicable law, we may be required to retain some of your Personal Information, and certain Personal Information is strictly necessary for us to fulfill the purposes described in this Notice; if we maintain any inaccurate information about you, request correction of that inaccurate Personal Information; for sensitive Personal Information that we collect, request that we limit our use of your sensitive Personal Information to that use which is necessary to perform the services or provide the goods reasonably expected by an average consumer who requests such goods or services and as otherwise authorized under applicable laws; request information about the Personal Information about you that we have disclosed for a business purpose and the categories of persons to whom it was disclosed for a business purpose; request information about the Personal Information about you that we have "sold" or "shared" (as such terms is defined under CCPA/CPRA) and the categories of third parties to whom the Personal Information was sold or shared. If you wish to know this information, please see Section 3 of this Privacy Notice; and opt-out of the "sale" or "sharing" of your Personal Information (as such terms is defined under applicable California laws), if applicable. As mentioned in Section 3, we have not sold any of your Personal Information. To opt out of “sharing” of your personal information, please see Section 3 of this Privacy Notice. You will not receive discriminatory treatment for exercising your rights under the CCPA. In order to verify your request, you will need to provide your legal first and last name, email address you use to correspond with Robert Half, your relationship with Robert Half, and the state you currently reside in. If you are submitting your request via the online form, after you submit the form, you will need to verify your email by clicking on a “Confirm Email” button in the verification email we will send you. If you authorize an agent to make an access or deletion request on your behalf, please have the authorized agent call the toll-free number at [1 (800) 803-9336](tel:18008039336) because Robert Half will need to verify the authorization before processing the request. The authorized agent will need to submit documentation evidencing your authorization of this agent to make the request and the authorized agent will need to verify their identity with Robert Half. Access to Notice in Alternative Formats. Individuals who need assistance accessing this Notice in an alternative format can do so by contacting Robert Half at [\[email protected\]](https://www.roberthalf.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). California "Shine the Light" law California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as California's "Shine the Light" law, permits residents of California to request certain details about information we may disclose to third parties for direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and would like to request this information, please contact us in accordance with the “Contact Us” section below. 

If you have any questions or complaints about the [Terms](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/terms) or the [Notice](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/privacy), or if you would like to update any Personal Information you have provided to us, please contact us at the mailing address or email address below. **Mailing Address:** Robert Half Inc. Attn: Terms of Use / Privacy Notice 2884 Sand Hill Road Suite 200 Menlo Park, California 94025 **Email Address:** [\[email protected\]](https://www.roberthalf.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) Please note that e-mail communications will not necessarily be secure; accordingly, you should not include credit card information or other sensitive information in your e-mail correspondence with us. 

[Browse Jobs](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/jobs) [Contract Talent](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/hire-talent/flexible-staffing) [Permanent Talent](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/hire-talent/full-time-staffing) [Consulting Solutions](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/consulting) [Finance & Accounting](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/accounting-finance) [Technology](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/tech-it) [Marketing & Creative](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/marketing-creative) [Administrative & Customer Support](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/administrative) [Legal](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/legal) [Discover Insights](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/insights) [Invoice](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/pay) [Job Directory](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/job-details-all) [Salary Guide](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/insights/salary-guide) [Time Reports](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/login) [Contact Us](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/contact) [About Robert Half](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/about/about-robert-half) [Leadership](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/about/leadership) [Careers With Us](https://careers.roberthalf.com/global/en/home) [Locations](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/locations) [Investor Center](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/about/investor-center) [Press](https://press.roberthalf.com/) [Our Brands](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/about/our-company/brands) [Supplier Relations](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/about/supplier-relations) [](https://www.facebook.com/pages/Robert-Half/182444181913924)[](https://www.linkedin.com/company/robert-half-international)[](https://twitter.com/roberthalf)[](https://www.youtube.com/roberthalfna)[](https://www.instagram.com/roberthalf/)[Fraud Alert](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/fraud-alert) [Government Notice](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/government-notice) [Privacy Notice](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/privacy) [Terms of Use](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/terms) Robert Half Inc. [An Equal Opportunity Employer](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/equal-opportunity-employer "equal-opportunity-employer") [M/F/Disability/Veterans.](https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/equal-opportunity-employer "equal-opportunity-employer")   [Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information](#) Australia - English Belgium - English Belgium - Nederlands Belgium - Français Brazil - Português Canada - English Canada - Français Chile - Español China - English China - 中文 France - Français Germany - Deutsch Hong Kong, China - English Ireland - English Japan - English Japan - 日本語 Luxembourg - Français Luxembourg - English Netherlands - English Netherlands - Nederlands New Zealand - English Singapore - English Switzerland - Deutsch Switzerland - English Switzerland - Français United Arab Emirates - English United Kingdom - English United States - English
